Osman KOYUNCU

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

E-mail: osmannnkoyuncuuu@gmail.com Phone: +90 530 236 28 78

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/osman-koyuncu/ Address: Turkey

GitHub: https://github.com/osmankoyuncuu

SUMMARY

As a Frontend Developer with over 2 years of experience, I am a passionate and fast-learning professional in the world of web development. My passion for creative design and user experience allows me to focus on the development of powerful, user-friendly web applications with an agile approach. With strong skills in **Next.js and Vue.js**, I work on projects that enable users to have immersive and functional web experiences. I always make sure to stay up to date with frontend technologies and trends and am constantly developing myself to gain new skills. I also enjoy collaborating and focus on contributing to the success of projects as a tight team player. I am strong at tasks such as understanding customer requirements, prioritizing users' needs and optimizing the technical feasibility of design. I am excited to use these skills to create effective and unique web projects in a rapidly changing digital world.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Rest Play March 2023 - Present

Frontend Developer

- Developed interactive, responsive and scalable frontend using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, Next.js and Vue.js.
- Created data visualization tools and integrated designs.

Upwork Aug 2022 – March 2023

Frontend Developer (Freelance)

- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Developed interactive, responsive and scalable frontend using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, React.
- Created data visualization tools and integrated designs.
- Increased speed of product lifecycle and 100% of the time delivered projects within deadline.
- Designed 5+ websites with HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, MaterialUI, Tailwind codes and Increased patient satisfaction scores by 30%.
- Applied state management throughout the projects using React States and Redux.
- Studied on Computational Thinking, Operating Systems, Version Control Systems(Git & Github),
 Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC),
- Used SCRUM & Agile methodologies and JIRA while working on individual & group projects.

Project Manager

- Worked the projects on were completed on time and completely.
- Worked Education in harmony with people from different and cultural levels.
- 500+ people were trained in line with their targets.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML | CSS3 | JavaScript | ReactJS | NextJS | VueJS | TypeScript | Redux | SASS | Bootstrap | Material-UI | Axios | Formik | Yup | Python | Linux | PostgreSQL | Git | GitHub | APIs | Firebase | Agile | Scrum | Jira | SDLC | OOP | Computer Science | Docker | Azure | Amazon S3

SOFT SKILLS

Analytical Thinking | Problem-Solving | Strong Communication | Project Management | Time Management | Adaptability | Collaboration & Teamwork | Creativity | Entrepreneurship | Business Discipline

PROJECTS

- Rest Play: (https://www.restplay.com/)
- Rest Poker: (https://rest.poker/)
- Blog App: (https://osman-blog-app.netlify.app/) In this project, the aim was to create blog posts using firebase realtime-database and display them on the dashboard. You can add, delete, update, favorite and comment on blog posts. In the project, firebase realtime-database library was used for storing data, material-ui library for styling, react-router library for page transitions, formic and yup libraries for form structure and validation, and react-toastify library for notifications. In addition, firebase was used for login and authorization processes. Skills/Tools: Firebase realtime-database library, Material-UI library, React-router library, Formik and yup libraries, React-toastify library, Firebase.
- Stock App: (https://stock-app-gules.vercel.app/) In this project, it is aimed to create a stock management panel. Users cab enter companies, products, brands and can control the amount of stock bought and sold from these products and see them graphically. Skills/Tools: React components, Redux Toolkit, Material UI library, formik-yup library, tremor library, axios library, react-toastify library.
- Last Fm: (https://last-fm-react.vercel.app/) In this project, Last.fm apiden lists artists and their albums. It lists the artists on the homepage with the infinete scrool method. Details of selected artists are shown on a separate page. Skills/Tools: React, React-router-dom, React Custom Hook, React-query, Redux/Toolkit, Tailwind
- Notes: (https://notes-wheat-one.vercel.app/) In this project, it is aimed for the user to keep and track their notes. It has the ability to create, edit and delete content and tags related to user notes. Can filter the notes it has by title and tags. Skills/Tools: React, Typescript, React-router-dom, Bootstrap, React-select-multi

EDUCATION

Anadolu Univesity	Sep 2018 – Aug 2019
Justice, Associate's degree	
University of National Defence	Sep 2011 – Aug 2015
Electronic Engineering, Bachelor's Degree	
CERTIFICATIONS	
Beginner Frontend Web Development Path – Patika.dev	Jan 2023
• Frontend Developer Course Certificate - Clarusway	Dec 2022
React Course Certificate - Clarusway	Nov 2022
JavaScript Course Certificate - Clarusway	Oct 2022
Javascript Certificate - Sololearn	Oct 2022

Turkish: Native

English: Intermediate